《神奇四侠》
Typical of Victor Von Doom to build a 30-foot statue of himself.
为自己建30英尺高的塑像 真是典型的维克多 方杜
Well, it's obviously aimed at first-time visitors...
很明显 是想让那些第一次的来访者...
to create feelings of smallness, inadequacy.
产生一种自惭形秽的感觉
Good thing it ain't working.
好在对我们没用
Reed, what are we doing here? This guy's fast-food, strip-mall science.
瑞德,我们干吗来这? 这家伙搞的都是些低级的科学
This wasn't our first stop, in case you forgot.
你别忘了 我们不是第一次上门求人了
Besides, Victor's not that bad. He's just a little larger than life.
再说,维克多也不是太坏 只是有点妄自尊大
My research suggests that exposure to a high-energy cosmic storm...
我的研究显示暴露在由 日冕太阳风所生成的...
borne on solar winds might have triggered the evolution of early planetary life.
高能量的宇宙风暴之下 可能会引发早期行星生命的演化
In six weeks, another cloud with the same elemental profile...
六个星期后 一类似上述特征的云团...
will pass Earth's orbit.
将经过地球轨道
A study conducted in space could fundamentally advance our knowledge...
若在太空进行研究 将会从根本上推进...
about the structure of the human genome, cure countless diseases...
我们对人类基因组结构的认识 治愈无数疾病...
extend human life, give kids a chance to live longer, stronger, healthier
延长寿命,让孩子们活得更长 更壮,更健康
Turn it off, please.
关掉,请
I don't think I have explained my proposal fully.
我想我还没把我的提议完全解释清楚
No, I think you have.
不,已经够清楚了
Same old Reed, always stretching, reaching for the stars...
你一点儿也没变 肩负着全世界...
with the weight of the world on his back.
总想着伸手去触摸星辰
But dreams don't pay the bills, do they?
但帐单不是由梦想来兑现的,不是吗?
You remember, when we were in school we talked about working together.
记不记得我们还在学校的时候 说过将来要一起合作
Well, that's what I was about to explain.
我正要跟你解释这个
The storm is deadly.
这个风暴是致命的
But the shields on your station's control room...
但你的空间站控制室外的防护罩...
are designed to protect any occupants inside.
是专门设计以保护 里面的人不受伤害
So it's not just my money you want.
所以你要的不光是我的钱
It's my toys.
还有我的"玩具"
Tell me, if NASA doesn't trust you, then why should l?
告诉我,如果宇航局不相信你 那凭什么要我信你?
That's my job, to stay a step ahead.
领先一步,这就是我的工作
To know what other men don't.
洞察别人所看不到的东西
I can't take this.
我可受不了这个
Ben, this is business, just work.
本,这是做生意,只是工作
He's right, Ben. It is just business.
他是对的,本 这只是生意
I think you both know my Director of Genetic Research, Susan Storm.
我想你们都认识 我的基因研究部的主管苏珊 斯多姆
One more thing he's got.
他比你又多了一样东西
- Hey, Susie. - Hey.
- 嗨,苏 - 嗨
It's so nice to see you. How's Debbie?
见到你真好 戴比怎么样?
- Great. - Great.
- 很好 - 很好
- How have you been? - Never better.
- 你过的好不好? - 再好不过
This isn't going to be a problem, is it?
这不会是个问题吧?
- No. - Not at all.
- 不 - 当然不会
Good.
好
Then you're just in time to hear the great Reed Richards...
你正好赶上,能听到 伟大的瑞德 理查德斯...
ask me for help.
向我求助
You know, you made a lot of folks at MlT feel like a junior high science fair.
你知道吗,你曾让很多麻省理工的学生 觉得自己像个科技展上的初中生
So you'll excuse me if I savour the moment.
这一刻让我有点得意 你可别介意
You back this mission and I'll sign over a fair percentage of any application.
你若支持这项计划 最后全部成果我会给你一个合理的提成
The number's 75%.
75%
And its applications and patents.
附加所有的应用成果和专利权
- What about his first-born? - Ben...
- 你怎么不把他榨干算了? - 本...
Come on.
算了
25% of a billion is enough to keep the lights on for a while, isn't it?
十亿美元的百分之二十五 够你们用你一阵了,不是吗?
Maybe even pay off your fourth mortgage on the Baxter Building.
也许你还能把巴克斯特大厦的 第四期按接款给付了呢
Deal?
成交?
Well, then. To our future.
好吧,为了我们的将来
Together!
大家共同的未来
It's funny how things turn out, isn't it?
事情变成这样挺有意思的,对吧?
Hilarious.
很滑稽
He knew about NASA. Maybe he made the call to shut us down.
他认识宇航局的人 没准就是他让我们被拒了
Ben, think about all the people we can help if this works.
本,想想看要是这件事成了 我们能帮助多少人!
Look, we got what we wanted. That's enough.
瞧,我们已经得到了想要的 这足够了
A few days in space, it'll be great. What's the worst that can happen?
能在太空中过几天,挺好的事 难道还会变糟?
If Reed's right, this little trip could double our stock offerings.
如果瑞德是对的 这次小旅行能让我们的股票翻倍
- And if he's not... - Reed's always right.
- 要是他错了呢? - 他错不了
Good thing he doesn't always know what he's got.
好在他一直都不清楚其背后的价值
Reed, you should know those solar winds have been picking up speed.
瑞德,你应该知道太阳风 已经在开始加速了
I factored them into my coordinates.
我已经把这些因素计算在内了
Right, of course you did. In theory.
当然,你算过,理论上
It's a little different once you're out there.
一旦到了太空里 事情就不完全一样了
- I can assure you l - When are we leaving?
- 我可以向你保证我… - 我们何日升空?
I'll be scheduling the launch...
我会负责发射日程的安排...
so you can call me in the morning for resources and crew.
你早上可以打电话给我 问关于资源和机组人员的事
- I think I remember the number. - It's been changed.
- 我想我记得你的号码 - 换过了已经
As far as crew, I was hoping Ben could pilot the mission.
至于机组人员的安排 我希望让本做驾驶员
We already have a pilot on our payroll, but you're welcome to ride shotgun.
我们已经雇用了一个飞行员 不过欢迎你来当副手
Remember my brother, Johnny?
记得我弟弟约翰尼吗?
Can't do it. Cannot do it.
不行,干不了
External SRBs, orbital system engines, it's just like the shuttle you flew.
外置固态火箭推进器,轨道系统引擎 和你飞过的航天飞机一样
No! I cannot take orders from the underwear model.
不,我可不会听一个内衣模特的指挥
- Come on now, Ben. - That wingnut washed out of NASA...
- 本,别这样 - 那臭小子因为带两个"维多利亚秘密"的...
for sneaking two Victoria's Secret wannabes into a flight simulator.
内衣女郎偷偷溜进飞行模拟器 而被宇航局扫地出门
Youthful high spirits.
年轻人好动嘛
They crashed it into a wall. A flight simulator.
结果撞到墙上去了 飞行模拟器!
When have I ever asked you to do something...
什么时候有过我要你做件什么事...
you absolutely said you could not do?
你说你绝对不能做的?
Five times.
五次
- I had it at four. - Well, this makes five.
- 我记得是四次 - 那这是第五次了
Attention, all personnel.
所有人员请注意
Commencing launch sequence in six hours.
6小时发射倒计时
I miss you already, Debs.
我已经开始想你了,戴比
Captain on the bridge!
机长驾到!
Digital camera: $254. Memory stick: $59.
数码相机:264元；记忆棒:59元
The look on your hard-ass former CO's face...
从前的硬汉指挥官竟然...
when he finds out he's your junior officer:
成为下属而郁闷的表情:
Priceless.
无价
Thank you. That's so sweet.
谢谢,你真好
I can handle the ship.
我能搞定这飞船
I can even handle Mr. Blond Ambition.
我也能搞定你这个野心勃勃的黄毛小子
But I don't know whether I should be flying or doing Swan Lake in these suits.
但我不知道穿上这衣服我是该 飞行还是跳天鹅湖
- I mean, who the hell came up with these? - Victor did.
- 我是说,谁他妈设计的这个 - 维克多
The synthetics act as a second skin, adapting to your body's individual needs.
这种人造纤维就像第二层皮肤 可以适应人体的不同需求
See, now that means it keeps the hot stuff hot...
这就是说 它能让该热的热...
and it keeps the cool stuff cool.
该冷的冷
Wow. Fantastic.
喔,真棒
Material made from self-regulating unstable molecules.
用可自我调节的不稳定分子制成的材料
I've been working on a formula for this.
我一直在研究这个
Great minds think alike.
英雄所见略同
- Here you go, Ben. - Thanks, sweetie.
- 你的,本 - 谢谢你,甜心
Reed.
瑞德
ETA until cosmic event: nine hours.
距宇宙风暴来临还有9小时
If you're good, maybe next time Daddy'll let you drive.
要是你表现地好 说不定老爸下次会让你飞行
You keep talking and there won't be a next time.
再废话多 就没下次了
Long way from the projection booth at the Hayden Planetarium, isn't it?
从发射间到海登天文馆 这一路走来真长啊,对吗?
Yes. Yes, it is.
是,是的没错
We can monitor the cloud's approach and observe the tests from here.
从这里我们可以监视云层的靠近 和观察试验
Is it safe?
安全吗?
The shields on the station should protect us.
空间站上的防护罩 应该可以保护我们
Should?
应该?
What's the matter, Ben? Getting paranoid in your old age?
你怎么了,本? 人老了,变得有点偏执了?
Let's start loading those samples. Get your suit ready, Ben.
我们开始搬运试验品吧 准备好你的工作服,本
So I see you're still doing all the heavy lifting.
我看你还在做这些搬运的重活
Maybe you should have stayed in the lab. Fieldwork never suited you.
也许你应该呆在试验室里 现场工作从来就不适合你
He does the talking, I do the walking. Got it?
他指挥,我来做 明白?
So take a walk, Ben.
那够你忙得了,本
Actually, if you'll all excuse me, I need to borrow Susan for a moment.
要是你们方便的话 我找苏珊有点事
Sure.
当然
Please tell me your guy's not trying to rekindle things with my sister again.
麻烦你告诉我,他不是又想 和我姐姐旧情复燃吧?
Of course not. It's strictly business.
当然不是,纯粹是公事
Yes, well, his eyes say differently, don't they?
那就好,不过,他的眼神不太对哦
Two hearts got busted last time. Maybe she's not over it, either.
那一次他们两个可都伤透了心 也许她也还没忘了他
Wow, Dr. Phil, that's deep. Let's think about that.
哇,心理医生,你还真深刻 试想一下
You got Victor, more money than God, stud of the year.
一个是维克多,富可敌国 年度杰出青年
And you got Reed, world's dumbest smart guy, worth less than a postage stamp.
一个是瑞德,世界上最笨的聪明人 一文不名
That's a real toss-up.
还真是势均力敌
Don't trouble your tiny little mind.
你就别伤你的小脑筋了
Don't wander off now, boy.
别走丢了,小伙子
Securing airlock chamber.
关闭气压隔离舱
Surprised I agreed to Reed's proposal?
我答应瑞德的提议,你很惊讶吗?
I understand the business reasons.
我知道生意的原因
Well, when you're looking at your future...
怪不得人们都寄希望于望未来...
it doesn't hurt to find closure about the past.
它总能帮你为过去划上句点
Susan, every man dreams he'll meet a woman he can give the world to.
苏珊,每个男人都梦想能遇到一个 可以托付整个世界的女人
In my case, it's not just a metaphor.
对我而言,这话不仅仅是个比喻
Opening viewing station shield.
打开观景台防护罩
That can't be right.
有点不对劲
Event threshold in T-minus 9 minutes, 47 seconds.
距风暴来临还有9分47秒
That's impossible. It should be seven hours.
这不可能,应该还有7个小时
We've been together two years now.
我们在一起也有两年了
It's been a good two years, Victor. The company's accomplished so much.
这两年真不错,维克多 你的公司有了这么大的成就
Right, of course, the company.
对,当然,公司
But, you see, I've come to realise that all the accomplishments in the world...
但,你瞧,我刚刚意识到 这么多成就若无人分享...
mean nothing without someone to share them with.
那也毫无意义
I've lived my life unafraid of taking big steps.
在我的人生中 我从不害怕踏出大步
Now it's time to take the biggest step of all.
现在,是我踏出最大一步的时候了
- Victor. - lf it helps, think of this as a promotion.
- 维克多 - 就当这是我升你的职
- Victor, l - I have four words.
- 维克多,我… - 我要说四个字
Four little words that can change our lives forever.
四个改变我们一生的字
The cloud is accelerating.
云层正在加速!
We've got minutes until it hits, not hours.
再过几分钟它就过来了 不是几个小时
Victor, that storm is deadly. We need to abort.
维克多,那个风暴有致命危险 要马上中止行动
Get a grip, Reed. We didn't come all this way to lose our nerve at the first glitch.
瑞德,冷静点,我们大老远过来 可不能出一点小问题就慌了神
Just close the shields.
关闭防护罩
- Ben is still out there. - So reel him in.
- 本还在外面 - 那就把他收进来
But we came here to do a job, so let's do it quickly.
我们到这来是有任务的 快点
Victor, Reed's right. We have less than six minutes!
维克多,瑞德是对的 我们还有不到6分钟
- Ben, you need to get inside now. - What's going on?
- 本,你马上进来! - 出什么事了?
I ain't done arranging your flowers yet, egghead.
我活还没干到一半呢,高材生
Ben, turn around!
本,往回走
Guys, I'm not gonna make it.
兄弟们,我回不去了
Ben, you gotta jump. It's the only way!
本,跳过来,这是唯一的办法
- What are you doing? - Closing the shields.
- 你在干什么? - 关闭防护罩
- You can't just leave them out there. - Watch me.
- 你不能把他们都留在外面 - 我能
- You can't help them any more than I can. - I can try.
- 我都帮不了他们,你又能做什么 - 我可以试!
Come on, Ben, you got it!
本,你行的!
Okay, Johnny, get ready to close the portal.
好,约翰尼,准备好关上入口
Wake up. Ben.
醒一醒,本
Rise and shine, big boy. How you feeling?
嘿,起床了,太阳照屁股了 大男孩,感觉怎么样?
Where am l?
我在哪?
Back on Earth. We're in quarantine. Victor's medical facility.
回到地球了,隔离中 维克多的医院里
Reed? Sue?
瑞德和苏呢?
They're fine. Everybody else is fine.
他们没事,大家都没事
What's wrong with me?
我怎么了?
I swear to you, Ben. They've done everything humanly possible.
我向你发誓,本 他们已经尽了最大努力
The best plastic surgeons in the world are here, Ben.
也给你做了世界上最好的整容手术
You had the best.
本,给你的都是最好的
- Give me that mirror. - I don't know if that's a good idea.
- 把镜子给我 - 我不知道这是不是个好主意
- They said the shock alone - I said give me that goddamn mirror!
- 他们说单单是精神刺激就… - 我说把那个该死的镜子给我!
Okay, Ben, just be strong.
好吧,本,坚强点
Unfortunately, the doctors just couldn't do anything to fix your face.
不幸的是 医生就是无法修复你的脸
- Hi. - Hey.
- 嗨 - 嘿
Nice do. I'm liking the grandpa look.
不错啊,我喜欢你老爷爷的新形象
What?
什么?
- How's she doing? - Stable and her vitals are strong.
- 她怎么样? - 稳定,而且各项生命指数也很强
Blood panels show no irradiation. Good.
全血球计数显示没有受到辐射,好的
- You'll step up this protocol every - Every four hours, yes.
- 你过来查这些记录是不是每隔… - 每四个小时,是的
We know what we're doing.
我们知道我们在干什么
Another day of observation and you're all clear.
再观察一天 你们就都可以出院了
Excuse me. More flowers from Mr. Von Doom.
打扰了 方杜先生又送花了
She's allergic to orchids.
她对兰花敏感
Put the sunflowers by her bed, they're her favourites.
放些向日葵在她床边 那是她的最爱
Well, Victor...
哦,维克多...
the bank would like to congratulate you...
银行要恭喜你...
on the fastest freefall since the Depression.
你的股票是自经济大萧条 以来掉的最快的
We can't even give your stock away.
我们想送都没人要
Ned, you know I can turn this around.
奈德,你知道我是可以扭转局面的
Well, you're going to have to, Victor, or we pull out.
你必须扭转,维克多 否则我们就撤资
You have a week.
你有一周时间
You're enjoying this, aren't you, Ned?
你幸灾乐祸,对吗?奈德?
One week.
一周
Where do we think we're going?
喔喔喔,你以为我们要上哪儿去啊?
I don't know if we've noticed...
我不知道"我们"注意到了没有
but the sickest runs this side of the Alps are right outside that window.
阿尔卑斯山这边最疯狂的那些滑雪者 就在我窗户外面
Yeah, I've noticed, but there are rules here.
是,我看到了 但是这里有这里的规矩
- You can't leave until we - Until we've finish the tests.
- 你要等… - 等到测试全部做完
I know, I've never been good with rules. You let me know how those come out.
但我一向都不爱循规蹈矩 结果出来了,你告诉我
- Do you wanna help me with this zipper? - You know, this is not a ski resort.
- 你能帮忙我拉拉链吗? - 你知道,这里可不是滑雪胜地
Not yet. Luckily, Grandma still sends care packages, though.
还不是,好在滑雪板 有奶奶用"爱心包裹"给我寄来
You know, it's amazing, for an 80-year-old woman, you'd be surprised...
你知道吗,真让人惊奇 一个80岁的老奶奶…
- You are trouble. - Trouble is my middle name.
- 你真是麻烦 - 嗯,我的中间名就是麻烦
You're hot!
你好热!
Why, thank you. So are you. And I'm not afraid to cry.
哦?谢谢,你也很热辣 而且我感情丰富,敢于流泪
No, I mean, you feel a little feverish.
不是,我是说你好像有点发烧
Well, I've never felt better in my life. My God, you smell good.
我一辈子还没感觉这么好过 天哪,你真香
Listen, when do you get off work?
听着,你什么时候下班?
- 4:00, but l - Tell you what.
- 4:00,但我… - 那么你听着
You meet me at 4:01 at the top of the mountain.
四点过一分的时候到山顶上来找我
That'll give you a minute to freshen up. This is yours, that's mine.
给你一分钟的打扮时间 这是你的,那是我的
Nurses!
小护士!
How long was I out?
我昏迷了多久?
Hey.
嘿
Three days. Man, I was worried about you.
3天,我真为你担心
- How are you feeling? - Solid.
- 感觉如何? - 挺坚实的
- That was a close one, though, huh? - Yeah.
- 这次还真惊险,啊? - 是啊
- What was that about? - I don't know.
- 到底怎么回事? - 我知道
I really don't know.
真不知道
I've been going over the figures again and again and they all add up.
我把那些数据反复看了一遍又一遍
I just don't understand. Maybe I should have aborted
就是弄不明白 或许我早该放弃…
Reed, it was a freak of nature. You couldn't have possibly predicted it.
瑞德,那是自然界纯偶然的事件 你不可能预测到的
Let it go.
算了
You know, you live through something like this...
知道吗,死里逃生之后 才能真的让你...
it really makes you appreciate having the right woman in your life.
为拥有生命中对的那个女人而感激
- Yeah, you and Debbie are perfect. - I'm not talking about Debbie.
- 是啊,你和戴比是天生一对 - 我不是在说戴比
What? Come on.
什么?算了吧
She's got a good thing with Victor.
他和维克多挺般配的
He's smart, he's powerful, he's successful
他聪明,有权势 也成功
Well, maybe you should date him then.
那么,或许你该和他恋爱
Ben, she ended up with the right guy.
本,她和维克多在一起是对的
Things worked out for the best.
他们会越来越好的
Do I have to do everything myself?
是不是每件事都得我亲自来做?
All right. I think you should stay to the right.
好吧,我看你就呆在我右边
The left might give you trouble.
在左边可能会有麻烦
- I think we should drop, like, 10 more feet. - Good.
- 我想还得下降10英尺左右 - 好的
Last one down springs for room service!
最后到温泉的人给钱叫客房服务
That's my future wife.
她是我未来的老婆
You're losing!
你要输了
All right, no more kid's stuff.
好了,别闹着玩了
Check this out.
看这个
You're on fire.
你着火了
Thanks! You're pretty good, too.
谢谢,你也挺不错
No, you're on fire. Look!
不是,你真的着火了,你看!
Care to join me?
想一起来吗?
I can only stay for one drink 'cause I have to meet Victor.
我只能喝一杯,我和维克多约好了
Well, wouldn't want to keep Vic waiting.
哦,可不能让维克多久等
Reed, what are you doing here?
瑞德,你在这干什么?
I thought...
我以为...
Great! Maybe you can join us.
太好了,我们一起吧
How's the lPO now?
IPO（首次公开募股）怎么样了?
It's falling. We're looking at low 20s.
还在跌,我们希望能停在20来块的样子
It's a good number considering the fallout from
这个数字还不错 考虑到这次的失败都怪…
From Reed's disaster?
怪瑞德捅出来的这个大漏子?
Get me on the a.m. shows, Larry King, the cover of the Journal.
帮我联系一个早上的访谈秀,拉里 金的 还有杂志的封面
I have to do something about this scar.
我得想办法遮住这个伤疤
Make sure they only shoot me from my left side.
确保他们只从左边拍我
Actually, the scar's tracking well.
事实上,这伤疤还能加深印象
People seem to think it humanises you.
人们似乎觉得它让你 显得更有人情味了
And that's a good thing?
还成了好事了?
You know, maybe you should get some rest.
你知道吗,也许你该休息一下
Later.
不行
First, I have some unfinished business.
首先,我还有些未完成的工作
A deal that needs closing.
有一桩买卖要结
Sir, I have always wondered, why Sue?
先生,我总是很奇怪,为什么是苏?
You could have any other woman in the world.
你可以得到世界上其他任何女人
That's why. Because I could have any other woman.
正因为如此 因为我能得到其他的女人
- No, let me tell the story. - No, let him tell the story.
- 不,我来说 - 不,让他说
- You all right? - Yeah, bad shrimp.
- 你没事吧? - 可能是虾不新鲜
I think I better go lie down.
我想我最好去躺躺
Excuse me.
不好意思
Oh, God!
哦,老天
So, you feeling better?
你感觉好点了吗?
Yes, thank you.
是啊,谢谢
Good.
好
That's...good.
那就…好
You always had a way with words.
你总是很会说话
Wow. I should be going because...
哦,我要走了...
I have to meet Victor.
我约了维克多
I'm really happy for you and Victor.
我挺为你和维克多高兴的
You're really happy for me and Victor?
你真的为我和维克多高兴?
I can tell you guys are enjoying what was the best part of our relationship.
我看得出来,你们俩有共同的热爱 也正如我们的恋爱关系中最美好的东西
- Which was? - Passion...
- 是? - 激情…
for science.
对科学的激情
You're such a dork, Reed.
你是个混蛋,瑞德
You never got it...
你从来就没搞清楚...
- and you never will... - Well, what did I say?
- 你永远也搞不清楚... - 我说什么了?
...unless it's explained to you in quantum physics.
...除非我用量子物理学来跟你解释
I just wanted to let you know that l
我只不过想让你知道我…
It's been two years, and all you can say is that you're happy...
已经两年了 现在你能说的就只是...
for me and some other guy?
你为我和什么别的男人在一起而高兴?
Victor may be a lot of things.
维克多也许有他不好的地方
But at least he's not afraid to fight for what he wants.
但至少他敢于去争取他想要的东西
It's nice to be wanted sometimes, Reed.
瑞德,有时候 被人需要的感觉真的很好
To be seen and heard.
受人注视,倾听
Look at me.
看着我
I can't.
看不到
What do you mean, you can't? Look at me!
什么叫看不到 看着我
Sue, look at your hands!
苏,快看你的手!
Hey, you guys.
嘿,你们俩
You are never gonna believe what just happened to me.
你们绝不会相信刚才发生在我身上的事
What?
什么?
Well, I can explain this.
哦,这个我可以解释
It has to be the cloud. It's fundamentally altered our DNA.
一定是那个风暴云 从根本上改变了我们的DNA
Let's not jump to conclusions.
我们先别忙着做结论
We need a massive amount of evidence before making that leap.
在下结论之前 我们要先掌握大量的证据才行
Guys, look!
喔噢,你们看!
Now, picture that, but everywhere.
再想象一下,到处都是
It was everywhere.
刚才就是到处都是
What?
什么?!
The cloud has fundamentally altered our DNA.
那个云层确实根本上 改变了我们的DNA
- Cool! - We need to find Ben.
- 酷! - 我们得去找本
And you know what, guys? I think I was flying.
还有你们知道吗? 我想我刚才飞起来了
I said, cut it out, Johnny.
把它灭了,约翰尼
I'm getting the hang of it.
我正研究窍门呢
- Ben, it's Reed. - Stop.
- 本,我是瑞德 - 别玩了!
- All right. - All right?
- 好吧 - 好吗?
- Yes. - God!
- 是 - 天!
- God? - What's wrong with you?
- 天? - 你有什么毛病啊?
- What? - Sue, do you know the code?
- 什么? - 苏,你知道密码吗?
I might.
可能
Ben, open up.
本,开门
You all right, Ben?
你没事吧,本?
Does somebody have keys to these doors?
你们谁有钥匙?
Anybody?
谁有?
Just break the glass. It can't be that thick.
就把玻璃砸了,不会很厚的
Give me another couple of seconds, guys. I almost got it.
再给我点时间 差不多就好了
That's gross.
恶心!
Ben?
本?
Look.
看
What is that thing?
那是什么?
What's going on?
怎么搞的?
What happened in here?
这里发生什么事了?
Victor, are you feeling all right?
维克多,你感觉还好吗?
I'm fine. Just a few scrapes, that's all.
我很好,就是有点擦伤,仅此而已
Ben did this.
这是本干的
He's had some kind of reaction to exposure from the cloud.
因为暴露在那个云层之下 使得他有些反应
We all have different symptoms.
我们都有不同的症状
Symptoms?
症状?
- Victor, I should have - Just find him.
- 维克多,我本应该… - 找到他
Anybody got any ideas where the big guy's going?
有人知道那个大家伙 大概会上哪吗?
He's going home.
他回家了
（大号男装）
You gotta be kidding me.
我靠,不是吧!?
Little buttons.
按键那么小
Hello, Operator?
接线员,你好
- Hello? - Debs?
- 喂? - 戴比?
- It's me. - Ben?
- 是我 - 本?
Are you all right? You sound a little different.
你还好吗?你的声音有点不同
- Listen, I need you to come out front. - Out front?
- 听着,我想让你下楼到门前来 - 楼下?
You're home, baby?
亲爱的,你回家了吗?
Yeah.
是啊
I got a surprise for you.
有个惊喜要给你
Yeah, I got a little one for you, too.
我也有一个要给你
Ben?
本?
Where are you?
你在哪?
I'm over here.
我在这儿
Don't come any closer for a sec, okay?
先别走过来,好吗?
It's gonna be a bit of a shock.
这会有点,有点让人震惊
Honey, what's going on?
亲爱的,怎么了?
Debs...
戴比...
remember when we used to say...
记得我们曾说过...
together forever no matter what?
不管发生什么都要永远在一起的吗?
Yeah.
是啊
Well...
那么...
Baby, you're scaring me.
亲爱的,你别吓我
Oh, my God.
噢,我的天哪
Deb, it's me. It's still me.
戴比,是我,我还是我
It was the accident. Let me explain.
这是个意外,你听我解释
- No! Don't touch me! - Debs!
- 不,别过来,别碰我 - 戴比!
I'm calling the police.
我叫警察了!
Everybody all right?
你还好吗?
I saw him. It's that guy over there!
我看见那个家伙在那边
Okay, so he was there last night.
那么他昨晚在那
Debbie's gonna meet us on the other side of the bridge.
戴比会在桥的另一端和我们碰头
Yeah, Ben.
对啊,本
"A few days in space. It'll be great.
"太空里过几天多好啊
What's the worst that could happen?"
难道还能有什么坏事发生?"
Hey, little guy.
嗨,小东西
You're not afraid of me, are you?
你不怕我,对不对?
Perfect.
很好
Thanks.
谢谢
Hey!
嗨
You think you've got problems? You take a good look, pal.
你以为就你有问题? 朋友,你看看我
How bad could it be, right?
再坏还能怎样,对不对?
I don't think you...
我看你不...
Okay, pal. Take it easy. No, don't go out there.
好吧,朋友,放轻松 别,别走到外面去
Look, I said stop, you fruitcake!
我说站住,你这果肉蛋糕
No. Come close.
不,过来点
That's further. Come closer.
反而远了,过来点
I said, stop! No!
我说,停住!不!
Come here.
过来
All right, calm down.
好的,冷静
You wanna be scared?
你想让我吓唬你?
- Fine! - No!
- 好! - 不!
Get back, everybody!
都回去,别过来
Get back in your vehicle. We'll tell you when you can go.
回到车上 我们会告诉你们何时可以通行
- What do we do now? - We're not going to get past these guys.
- 我们现在怎么办? - 这里人这么多,我们过不去
But you could.
不过你可以
Sorry about the truck, pal. Come on.
朋友,弄坏你的卡车,对不起
A little help, here? You wanna hit the button, sir?
你要帮忙吗? 你想按那个纽吗,先生?
It's stuck.
卡住了
Sue, your clothes. Lose them.
苏,你的衣服,把它脱了
Right.
好的
This is so wrong.
这可不好
- Wow, you've been working out. - Shut up!
- 喔,你有在健身 - 闭嘴
All right.
等等
All right, freeze!
别动!
Now just...
现在...
Just put the man in the seat down.
把那个椅子上的男人放下
Do it!
快点!
Any more great ideas?
你还有什么好主意?
Why don't you strip down and have a 100 people stare at you?
你怎么不把衣服脱了 让几百个人盯着你看?
- Sue. - What?
- 苏 - 什么?
I'm gonna need therapy.
我得去找个心理医生
Come on, let's get out of here.
跟我来
Excuse me. Coming through.
让一让,让我过去
All right, now just back away from him.
好的,现在,呃,往后退
And I want you to put your hands on your head...
把你的手举起来放在头上...
954 approaching scene.
954分队,马上到达事发地点
I still can't believe you made me do that.
真不敢相信,你让我出那样的丑
We got through, didn't we? Just find Ben.
我们总算过来了,不是吗? 找到本再说
Ben!
本!
Mum.
妈妈
Stay here, okay?
呆在这别动,好吗?
I'm coming.
我来了
Hold on.
坚持住
Hang on!
坚持住!
I got you.
我抓住你了
Get down on the ground.
趴在地上
Get down on the ground now!
趴在地上,快!
Ben.
本
I swear to you...
我向你保证...
I will do everything in my power...
我会尽我所能...
until there is not a breath left in me.
只要我还有一口气
You're going to be Ben again.
我就一定让你变回原来的本
I told you I felt fine.
我告诉你我没事
Where are your ears?
你的耳朵上哪去了?
There are some folks outside that want to talk to you.
有些人在外面想和你们谈谈
We're not going public with this.
这件事我们不想公开
We're scientists, not celebrities.
我们是科学家,不是名人
It's too late, son.
已经太晚了,小伙子
Look.
看
...when a New York Fire Department ladder truck...
...纽约消防队的一辆云梯车...
See that?
看到了?
...became part of the tragedy.
...不幸成了悲剧的一部分
But the rescue itselfis not the story.
但是今天的焦点不在救援
One of the four stretched to an amazing length...
四人中的一个把身体伸展到惊人的长度...
That's what they're calling you. "The Fantastic Four."
这是他们给你们取的名字:"神奇四侠"
- Cool. - No, wait! Where are you going?
- 酷 - 等等,你上哪去?
I'm gonna go talk to them.
去接受采访啊
No, we should think this through.
别忙,我们先把事情搞清楚
That's great. Brainstorm.
很好,那就集体讨论
Get back here, right now. Johnny!
马上给我回来,约翰尼!
Settle down.
静一静
Do you believe this?
真让人不敢相信
Which one of you is the leader?
你们谁是头儿?
That would be me.
正是在下
No, seriously.
不,我说真的
Okay, son. You're on.
好吧,小伙子,你上
During our recent mission to the Von Doom space station...
呃,在最近一次在 方杜空间站上的行动中...
we were exposed to as yet unidentified radioactive energy.
我们被暴露在目前尚不明确的 放射性能量之下
- What happened on the bridge? - How can you stretch?
- 桥上到底发生了什么? - 为什么你的身体可以延展?
- Were you really on fire? - ls it true you can fly?
- 你真的可以控制火? - 你能飞,是真的吗?
Yeah, I'm working on it. It's actually really difficult.
是啊,我正在尝试 实际上这很有点难度
No, actually, we do not know much more than you do at this point.
不,事实上,我们现在 所知道的也不比你们多
Sir, Larry King just cancelled.
先生,拉里 金把访谈取消了
Apparently, there's a bigger story.
很明显现在有更轰动的头条
Actually, here they come now. You had to see it to believe it, folks.
现在,他们来了 朋友们,眼见为实
The man...named The Fantastic Four...
...神奇四侠...
We'll be going directly to our lab to diagnose our symptoms.
我们会马上到实验室里 去研究分析我们的症状
Symptoms? Is this some kind of disease?
症状?这难道是一种什么疾病吗?
No. It's not a disease.
不,这不是疾病
If having special powers is a disease, then, yeah, we got it bad.
如果说有超能力也是病的话 是,我们病入膏肓了
Excuse me, that thing doesn't look so fantastic.
可那个东西看起来可不神奇
Ben Grimm is a genuine American hero.
本 格莱姆是真正的美国英雄!
What he means is, every team needs a mascot.
他的意思是说每个队伍 都要有个吉祥物嘛
A new day is dawning. The day of The Fantastic Four.
新的时代来临了 这是"神奇四侠"的时代
Look!
等等!
We went up to space to find a way to understand DNA...
我们到太空去是为了 寻找认识DNA的方法...
cure disease, save lives.
治愈疾病,挽救生命
Well, now it's our DNA, our disease, our lives on the line.
但现在,我们的DNA,我们的病 我们的生命悬于一线
Thank you. No more questions.
谢谢,别再问了
This is how you turn things around?
你就是这样扭转局面?
These freaks on the front page? Your company's in the obituaries?
这几个怪东西占满了头条 而你的公司消息只有在讣告栏里去找?
I was planning to use the publicity.
我是打算利用公众舆论
The board's in agreement, the bank's lost enough already.
董事会已经达成一致了 银行已经损失了很多钱了
- Wait a minute. - It's too late, Victor.
- 等等 - 太迟了,维克多
Do you know how much money I've invested in this company?
你知道我在这个公司里 投了多少钱吗?
Victor, stop.
维克多,够了
This isn't a negotiation. It's a notification.
这不是谈判,这是通知
We're pulling out.
我们要撤资
Is all that for you, Dr. Richards?
都是来看你吧,理查德斯博士?
I'm afraid so.
恐怕是的
Come on, Ben, smile. They want to like you, Ben. Say hi.
本,别这样,笑一笑嘛 他们都想喜欢你,打个招呼
Don't do drugs.
不要吸毒!
Welcome back to the Baxter, Dr. Richards.
欢迎回到巴克斯特大厦,理查德斯博士
I've got the usual for you.
这是你的,照旧
Good to have you back, sir.
欢迎回家,先生
Thanks, Willie.
谢谢,威利
（最后通知）
We had a tough year.
这一年我们很艰苦
Yeah, like nine straight.
是啊,连着九年
Either we're moving really fast or not at all.
要么就是我们上的飞快 要么就是动都没动
（超载）
I'll take the stairs.
我爬楼梯
How come Ben can't turn it on and off like we can?
为什么本不能像 我们这样随意切换呢?
That's what we're here to find out.
这正是我们要搞清楚的
I mean, if it happened to him...
我的意思是,如果他是这样...
What? You mean, like, we won't be able to turn it off, either?
怎么?你是说我们 也可能不能随意切换?
That would save time.
那就省时了
You don't really wanna walk around on fire for the rest of your life, do you?
你不会真想一辈子 都带着火到处跑吧?
- ls that a trick question? - Grow up.
- 你是想刁难我吗? - 成熟点吧
Come on. Am I the only guy who thinks this is cool?
少来了,难道就我一个人 觉得这是件挺酷的事吗?
We should stay here until we can define the extent of our changes...
我们得待在这直到 我们明确自己得变化...
and figure out how to reverse them.
和找出撤销的办法
But I have to warn you, it's gonna be a little crowded in some areas.
但我要事先警告你们 有些地方可能会有点挤
So, what do you think?
你觉得如何?
I don't know, Reed, I think you might be bringing your work home with you.
我不知道,瑞德 但我想你可能把工作带到家里来了
Come on. Let me show you guys where you'll be staying.
跟我来,我带你们去你们住的地方
Busy guy.
大忙人啊
Mr. Von Doom, would you like to comment on the recent failure of your lPO?
方杜先生,你对最近的 IPO下跌有什么看法?
What about the rumours of a takeover?
你怎么看有关你公司被接管的谣传?
God, I was so worried about you.
天哪,我真替你担心
Victor. I'm sorry I didn't get a chance to call.
维克多,对不起 我没机会给你个打电话
Please.
别
No apologies.
不用道歉
I've arranged for your things to be moved to one of my condos.
我已经安排好了 把你东西搬到我的公寓楼去
You'll have round-the-clock care.
那里有24小时的特护
Thank you. That's very generous of you.
谢谢你,你好意我心领了
But I think I should stay here with my brother...
不过,我想留在这里和我弟弟一起...
until we get a handle on things.
直到我们对事情有所掌握为止
Susan, I think you should let my doctors have a look at you.
苏珊,我觉得你最好让我的医生 给你检查一下
Victor, what are you doing here?
维克多,你到这干什么来了?
I'm starting to wonder the same thing.
我也想问这个问题
How much do you know about what happened to you?
你对发生在你们身上的事 有多少了解?
Not much.
不多
We need to run tests to see the extent of the damage.
我们要做些测试 看看损伤的程度
Well, you let me know what I can do. We're all in this together now.
好吧,有什么需要我做的你告诉我 我们现在都在一条船上
Victor, wait.
维克多,等等
I just wanted to say I'm sorry the mission didn't go as planned.
我想说,对不起 这次行动没能像计划中的那样
Didn't go as planned? It was a catastrophe.
不像计划中的?它是个大灾难!
You ruined the lives of four people.
你毁了四个人的生活
With all due respect, we're both to blame. I told you to abort.
客气的说,我们都有责任 我告诉过你中止的
Abort?
中止?
I put my company, my name, billions of dollars on the line.
我把我的公司,我的名誉 几十亿的资金都投了进去
I will not let you make me look like a fool.
我可不能让你把我 弄的像个傻子一样
Victor, if we can understand
维克多,要是我们能把它搞明白…
I don't wanna understand it! This isn't one of your science projects!
我不想弄明白 这不是你的什么科研计划
I just wanna fix it. Fast!
我只想补救它,要快!
Is there a problem?
有什么问题吗?
No.
没
No problem, Ben.
没问题,本
Just pay your damn electric bill and get to work on finding a cure.
赶快付清你的电费 好回去工作
He's heating up from his core.
他的热能来自于内核
And his vitals are completely normal.
而各项生命指数完全正常
If we're going to identify the source of the mutation...
若要找出突变的来源...
we need to isolate your recombinant DNA...
我们必须分离你的重组DNA...
so we can activate positional genomes.
这样我们就能激活定位基因组
We have to do a physical in order to see what got zapped.
我们要给你做个身体检查 看看有什么坏了
Why didn't you just say so?
哦,你就直说嘛
His internal organs are completely solid.
他的内部器官完全是固态的
How bad is it?
有多严重啊?
You know, I used to smoke.
你知道,我以前抽烟的
It's not invisibility per se.
这不能算是完全的隐身
You should be able to bend light around other objects, even people...
你应该可以把物体四周的光线挡在外面 甚至是人周围的...
if you could control your emotional state better.
要是你能更好地控制地你情绪
Excuse me?
你说什么?
I'm saying, if you had a little more self-control, you could locate the trigger.
我是说要是你有更好的自控能力 你就能知道是什么会触发你隐身
Can you remember your exact emotions on the bridge?
你记得你当时在桥上的情绪吗?
Anger.
气愤
Rage.
激怒
Frustration.
沮丧
Okay. Is there any way to duplicate that feeling?
好的,你能不能复制这些情绪?
Some memory or...
从记忆或者...
I'm sure I can come up with something.
我肯定我能记起一些事来
- You feel anything? - Nope.
- 有感觉吗? - 没
Okay.
好吧
It's hotter than I anticipated.
比我预想的还要热
- Okay, Johnny, back it down. - I can go hotter!
- 好了,约翰尼,把温度降下来 - 我还可以更热!
Johnny, just back it down.
约翰尼,快停下来
- Johnny, back it down right now! - Johnny!
- 约翰尼,立刻停止! - 约翰尼!
Buzz kill! You guys are cramping my style.
超凡本领 你们两个真扫兴
Johnny, you were at 4,000 Kelvin.
约翰尼你的温度到了4000开了（绝对温标）
Any hotter and you're approaching supernova.
再热一点,你就接近超新星了
- Sweet! - No, not sweet!
- 挺好! - 不,不好!
That's the temperature of the sun.
那是太阳的温度
Not only could you kill yourself...
不仅你自己会丧命...
but you could set fire to Earth's atmosphere...
你还会把大气层都点着了...
and destroy all human life as we know it.
摧毁地球上的一切生物
Got it. Supernova: bad.
知道了,超新星:不好
How's that coming?
怎么样了?
- I'm so sorry. Are you okay? - Yeah, fine.
- 对不起,你没事吧? - 没事
- You sure? - Yeah.
- 真没事吗? - 真的
I...
我...
You probably thought that was some form of latent hostility.
你大概会以为我对你有敌意吧
What in the world would give me that idea?
为什么这么说?
I mean, you broke up with me, right?
我是说,是你要和我分手的 对吗?
- Are you kidding? - No.
- 你在说笑吗? - 不
I distinctly remember, you walked out my door, ergo
我清楚地记得 是你离开了我,因此…
I was ready for the next step, you weren't. Ergo, I walked.
我已准备好更进一步的关系,而你没 因此,我离开了
I think it was a little bit more complicated than that.
我认为情况要比这个复杂点
I just wanted to share an apartment. What was so complicated about that?
我只不过是想和你搬到一起住 有什么好复杂的?
- There were a lot of variables to consider. - No, there weren't.
- 还有很多变量要考虑 - 不,没有
There was you and me. There were no variables, no math.
这里面只有你和我 没有变量,没有数学
It was actually the simplest thing in the world.
实际上 这是世界上最简单的事情
But like always, Reed, your head got in the way.
可是,瑞德,一如既往 你考虑太多了
- No, it didn't. - Then what was it?
- 不,我没有 - 那到底是为什么?
Did you feel anything when I left?
我走的时候你有感觉吗?
Do you feel anything right now?
你现在有感觉吗?
Hey, guys.
嘿
I think we have a serious problem.
我想我们有大麻烦了
So what's the prognosis?
后果会怎样?
Your tissue, your organs, your entire biophysical structure is changing.
你的组织,你的器官 还有你整个的生理结构都在起变化
Every system is still functioning somehow.
但不知何故 每个系统都还在正常工作
And it's changing into?
它最后会变成?
I don't really know.
我也不清楚
Some kind of organic-metallic alloy...
可能是某种有机的合金物质...
stronger than titanium or carbon steel, harder than diamonds.
比钛和钢还要强 比钻石还要硬
Like the shields Reed said would protect us.
就像瑞德说的那个 可以保护我们的防护罩一样
How long?
还要多久
At this rate, the infection could be complete in two, maybe three weeks.
照这个速度,两,三个星期 就会全部感染了
What do you mean complete?
你说全部是什么意思?
I wish I could tell you.
我也想知道
I can't pretend to know what we're dealing with here.
我不能在这里不懂装懂
I'll have to notify the CDC.
我得向CDC报告
- What? - Centre for Disease Control.
- 什么? - 疾病控制中心
I know what it is.
这个我知道
If this thing is contagious, we may have a big problem on our hands.
如果这个东西是有传染性的 我们可就遇到大麻烦了
We're talking about an epidemic here.
我们说得是温疫
Look at me.
看着我
I have a life.
我有我的生活
I'm the face of a billion-dollar company.
我代表着一个价值几十亿的公司
We need to keep this confidential.
这件事要保密
Victor, this disease is progressive, degenerative. I have to notify someone
维克多,你的病情正在发展,正在恶化 我必须通知…
That's terrible news.
真是个坏消息
But I think I'll get a second opinion.
但是我另有主意
Our uniforms were exposed to the storm, like us.
我们的制服同样 暴露在风暴云之下
So they can transform like us.
因此它们也可以 像我们一样变形
Becoming invisible, changing size on demand or remaining impervious to flame.
可以隐形,或是任意伸展 或是有极强的防火抗高温能力
You guys look like an '80s rock band.
你们几个看起来 像80年代的摇滚乐队
You know, Ben, this material stretches.
本,要知道这个材料是可以伸缩的
I'm sure I can figure out a way to make it fit.
我相信我一定可以 想到办法让你穿的下
I wouldn't be caught dead wearing that.
我怀疑,打死我也不会穿的
I love these costumes. They're missing something, though. Needs, like, spice.
我喜欢这个造型 可是好像还缺了点什么,不够特别
They're not costumes.
它们不是戏服
You can't use your powers in public, Johnny.
你不能在公众场合用你的超能力,约翰尼
- You guys are worse than NASA. - You could burn somebody.
- 你们几个比宇航局还要烦人 - 你会误伤别人
Maybe it's missing a utility belt.
也许还需要条条多功能皮带什么的
Here you go, there's your change.
呐,找你的钱
Can I help you, buddy?
需要什么,老兄?
- Oh, my. - It's Sue Storm, it's the lnvisible Woman!
- 喔 - 斯多姆小姐,那个会隐身的女孩
Sue Storm, it is you. Listen, my kid loves you!
是你 我的孩子很喜欢你
I can't believe I'm doing this again.
真不敢相信,又要脱一次!
Reed, we really can't go outside anymore.
瑞德,我们真的不能出门了
We are on the cover of every publication from People
所有的杂志封面都是我们
All right, I'm here, let's make this quick. I got a lot of places to go today.
好吧,我来了,快点说 我今天还有很多地方要去呢
Oh, wait. I don't go anywhere.
哦,等等,我哪也不去
Johnny, it's imperative that we stay inside for the foreseeable future.
约翰尼,为了安全起见 我们必须呆在这里
I know, but when you said that last time, my brain heard "a week."
上次听你说的是 只呆一周!
Johnny, it's too dangerous for you to be in public.
约翰尼,到外面去对你来说太危险了
You've been saying that for years.
这话你都说了好几年了
What worries me is that our powers are evolving.
让我担心的是 我们的超能力还在演化
I know!
我知道!
I am so close to flying, guys, I can taste it.
我就差那么一点就飞起来了 我能体会到
- You can't fly. - Yet.
- 你不能飞 - 目前不
Johnny, can you put that napkin out?
约翰尼,你能把那个先灭了吗?
Jesus.
噢,天哪
So what's going on, Reed? How're you going to cure us?
瑞德,你研究地怎么样了? 你打算怎么治我们?
I'm going to build a machine to recreate the storm.
我打算造一台机器 用它再制造一次风暴
The cosmic rays will travel from this generator to this chamber.
宇宙射线将从这个发生器 传到这个舱里
What, no pop-ups?
哦,图上怎么没有注释?
- lf I can reverse the wave signal - lt'll return us back to normal.
- 如果我能反转波段信号… - 这样就能把我们变回正常的样子
Right. But what are the risks?
不错,可是有什么风险?
Even a small miscalculation could increase our symptoms exponentially...
即使是最小的计算错误 也会导致症状成倍地加深...
or perhaps even kill us.
甚至让我们丧命
Now, dying. That's bad, right?
送命,这个不好,对不对?
I say we just let sleeping dogs lie, guys.
我说就这么得过且过吧,哥们
So how long till this contraption's up and running?
这个设备要再过多久才能开始工作?
- I don't know, it's hard to say. - How long, Reed?
- 不知道,很难说 - 多久?瑞德
- I don't know. - You don't know?
- 我不知道 - 你不知道?
- You don't want this to get worse. - Worse than that?
- 你不想情况恶化吧 - 比他那样还糟?
Guys, look, we're gonna be stuck here for a while, so let's just try and get along.
我们还得被困在这儿一阵子 让我们好好相处,好不好
- You could knock! - Sorry!
- 你不会敲门吗 - 对不起
Johnny!
约翰尼!
More bad news for Von Doom lndustries today as Ned Cecil announced...
今天又有更多的 关于方杜集团的负面消息...
that his group ofinvestors would seek to gain control...
耐德 西赛尔宣布 他的投资顾问组将接管...
of Victor Von Doom 's numerous technology companies.
方杜先生的各个科技公司
Earlier, the lPO was pulled from the market...
方杜集团早先的IPO发售...
after the steady decline of its projected opening price.
也处于不断下跌的状态
Von Doom lndustries was never able to overcome the negative publicity...
方杜集团将永不可能 克服这一次负面消息的影响...
Interesting.
有意思
Hello?
有人吗?
Victor?
维克多?
What's with these lights, huh?
这些灯怎么了?
About the lPO, no hard feelings, right?
关于IPO的事 不要太在意
Nothing personal.
绝非个人恩怨
You know, you could always move back to Latveria.
你知道你总还可以回 你拉脱维亚的老家去
Start fresh.
从头再来
Maybe that's where you belong, the old country.
也许你只属于那里 落后的国家
Nothing personal, Ned.
绝非个人恩怨,奈德
But I'm not going anywhere.
不过我哪儿也不去
...assassinated the competition everywhere this season.
...这个赛季到处都是竞争
Truly unbelievable. The crowd is going nuts here at the arena.
难以置信 竞技场的观众为之疯狂
I tell you, if there's anybody out there who can do what these guys do...
我说,要是有人也能像他们这样...
we dare you to come on down here. Look at this spread-eagle...
看看展翅的雄鹰...
no arm, back of the seat. Motorbike grab, landed...
那也过来露两手...
I got to get out of here.
我要离开这里
Hey, pretty boy, let's see what you got.
嘿,帅哥,让我看看你本事
Where's your hot sister and the monster?
你的美女姐姐和那怪物呢?
Let's go!
我们走
All right.
好了
I want you all to make a lot ofnoise now for a very special guest.
我要你们用最热烈的掌声 欢迎一位特别来宾
Mr. Johnny Storm from The Fantastic Four!
来自"神奇四侠"的 约翰尼 斯多姆先生
Look at that lift!
看这个挺身!
That was fantastic!
太神奇了!
But, Johnny, come on. That's old school.
不过,约翰尼,这是老一套了
Show us something new.
给我们看点新玩意儿
Something new.
新玩意
You got it.
好嘞
Come on, Johnny, come on!
喔喔,约翰尼,真精彩
Is he flying?
他是在飞吗?
Wait, no!
等等,没有
That's dangerous.
真危险
I'm okay, I'm all right, I'm good.
不要紧,我没事,我很好
He's okay! He's all right!
他没事,他很好
Johnny Storm, ladies and gentlemen!
女士们先生们,约翰尼 斯多姆
I have to give you props, Johnny! You were on fire!
我要为你鼓掌,约翰尼 你可真火
- He didn't. - Oh, yes, he did.
- 他不听话 - 哦,没错,不听话
- Flame Boy never listens. - What did he do to his uniform?
- 火焰小子从来就不听指挥 - 他把他的制服怎么了?
Johnny, I've gotta ask you about this outfit.
约翰尼,跟我说说你这个服装
Yeah, it's sort of Armani meets astronaut.
好啊,有点类似于阿玛尼 和宇航员的结合体
So what are your superhero names?
你们这些超级英雄的名字各是什么?
They call me The Human Torch. Ladies call me Torch.
他们叫我火把人 女士们则叫我火炬
What about the rest of the team?
其他的队员呢?
- That's the lnvisible Girl. - Girl?
- 那是隐身女孩 - 女孩?
What about your leader, Reed Richards? I hear you call him Mr. Fantastic.
那你们的头儿,瑞德 理查德斯呢? 听说你们叫他神奇先生
- Could've been worse. - I guess.
- 估计更难听 - 我想是的
Is it true what they say about him that he can expand any part ofhis anatomy?
人们说他可以自由伸展 身体的任何部分,对吗?
Well, I've always found him to be a little limp.
是吧,我也一直觉得他有点 柔
What is that? What do you call that thing?
那是什么?你们怎么称呼那个东西?
That's it. The Thing.
这就是它的名字了:"东西"
Yeah, you think this is bad, you should ha ve seen him before.
这还不算太糟 你们没看见他以前的样子
Okay. Now I'm gonna go kill him.
我这就去宰了他!
There he is.
他在那!
- Johnny! - Can we talk about this later, guys?
- 约翰尼 - 我等会再跟你们说,行吗?
- No. We can't talk about this later. - We can do this at home.
- 不行,我们现在就要谈! - 我们可以回家再谈
- What are you thinking? - Where's my ride?
- 你在想什么? - 我的车呢?
You think that's funny, Pebbles?
你觉得这样有意思吗,石头人?
- Johnny! - What?
- 约翰尼! - 什么?
You gave us names? You don't think.
你给我们取绰号?你不用脑子的!
So now you're the face of The Fantastic Four?
你是神奇四侠的脸面?
A face that's about to be broken!
脸面马上就要破相了!
Look, this isn't permanent, Johnny.
这些能力不是永久性的,约翰尼
We need to be careful until we're normal again.
在回复正常之前 我们要格外小心
What if I don't wanna be normal? I didn't turn into a monster!
要是我不想回复正常呢 我又没变成一个怪物
Ben!
本!
Did you just...
你刚才是不是...
Johnny, stop it.
约翰尼,住手
- That's it, Tinkerbell! - No, Ben.
- 够了,臭小子 - 别,本
You wanna fly? Then fly!
你想飞?那就飞吧
Wait a minute, guys! Ben, don't do this!
等等,本,别这样
Let's see if we can get blood from a stone.
让我们看看石头会不会流血
Let's see. Bring it, burnout!
来吧,烧吧
You two need a time-out!
你们俩暂停一下!
Talk to blockhead, he started it.
去跟那个傻子讲 他起头的
I don't care. Damn it, Johnny.
我不管,该死的,约翰尼
Ben, wait!
本,等等
What?
什么?
You need to control yourself and think before you act.
你要有点自控 动手之前先想想
Yeah, but see, that's your problem. You always think, you never act.
对,但这正是你的问题所在 你总是想,从来不做
What if we got these powers for a reason? What if it's like some higher calling?
如果我们得到这些超能力是有原因的呢? 如果这是上天的赋予的责任?
A higher calling? Like getting girls and making money?
责任? 就像泡马子,捞外快?
Is there any higher?
还有更高的?
You know what, Reed? This is who we are.
知道吗?瑞德 我们就这样了
Accept it.
接受它
Or better yet, enjoy it.
要么更好,享受它
Wait, Ben, slow down. He didn't mean it.
等等,本,慢一点 他不是有意的
You know Johnny. He's always been a hothead.
你知道约翰尼,他总是头脑发热
It ain't him. It's them!
我知道,我是烦他们!
I can't live like this.
我受不了这样的生活
Just give Reed a little more time. You know how he works.
给瑞德一点时间 你知道他做事的风格了
Analysing every little step before he takes one.
每走一步之前都要分析全局
- It's easy for you to be patient. - No, it's not!
- 你当然不着急 - 不,不是
I thought I was done waiting for Reed, but l...
我以为我再也不用等待瑞德了 但是我...
- We're all in this together, Ben. - Together?
- 我们是情况是一样的,本 - 一样?
Susie, look at me. You got no idea what l'd...
苏,你看看我 你不知道我...
What I'd give to be invisible.
我是多想变成隐身人啊
Thank you, gentlemen.
先生们,谢谢
I'm just gonna pick up a few things...
我就来拿一两样东西...
for some friends.
给我几个朋友
（MK457 热能追踪导弹）
（危险:超制冷体）
Perfect.
完美!
That's not funny.
这一点也不好笑
This is Ben Grimm here.
这位是本 格瑞姆
The first mook from Brooklyn to go into outer space.
第一位从布鲁克林到外太空去的人!
So pay him some respect.
所以请尊敬他!
Just give me the usual and I'm out.
给我照旧,我马上就走
All right.
好吧
- Make it a double. - Make it a triple.
- 给我双份 - 给他三份
- Put it on my tab, Ernie. - All right, Alicia.
- 算在我的账上,厄尼 - 知道了,甜心
Appreciate it.
谢谢
No problem.
不客气
It's okay, Ben.
没关系,本
If there's a God, he hates me.
如果真有上帝的话,他讨厌我
She is not so into hate.
她可不讨厌什么
If you could see me, you wouldn't be saying that.
要是你能看见我的话 你就不会这么说了
Then let me see you.
那就让我看看你吧
Can l?
可以吗?
- Careful. - It's okay.
- 慢点 - 好的
So sad.
那么悲伤
You know, being different isn't always a bad thing.
你知道吗? 与众不同,并不总是坏事
Trust me. This ain't one of them times.
相信我,这次是的
Not if you don't want it to be.
要是你不当它是坏事,它就不是
- All right, Ernie, I'm out of here. - I'll take you.
- 好了,厄尼,我走了 - 我送你出去
See you later, Benny.
再见,本
I'm Alicia, by the way.
顺便告诉你,我叫阿丽西亚
Thanks, Ernie.
谢谢你,厄尼
（维克多·方·杜  拉脱维亚人民感谢你的人道主义贡献）
Reed got what he wanted.
瑞德得到了他要的东西
And everything he wanted...
他所要的…
he took from me.
都从我这里夺走
Now it's time to take it back.
现在我要把这一切都拿回来
But first, I need to get rid of his bodyguard.
首先,要除掉的是他的保镖
This seat taken?
这个位子有人吗?
What are you doing here?
你来这干什么?
I was worried about you.
我担心你
You were worried about me? That's sweet.
你担心我? 让人感动
Come on. Let me buy you something to eat.
来,你要吃点什么,我请
Looks like you could use the company.
看起来你需要人陪
Reed?
瑞德?
- I was just resting my eyes. - So I see.
- 我只是想让眼睛休息一下 - 我知道
The new readouts look very promising.
新出的数据看起来很好
Not promising enough.
还不够好
When are the next tests?
接下来的测试在什么时候?
I've run out of plans.
我已经没有办法了
So I was thinking maybe...
所以我在想也许...
There's always me.
总可以拿自己来试验
No. It's too soon.
不,太仓促了
- Reed? - I should get back to work.
- 瑞德? - 我得继续工作
- You need a break. - Sue, not now, please.
- 你需要休息 - 苏,现在不行
Come on. Let's go.
来,我们走
Remember our first date here?
记得我们第一次在这约会?
God, I was nervous.
我好紧张
You know, I bribed the projectionist $10 to keep the place open late.
你知道吗?我给了看门的10美元 让他晚些关门
Really? I gave him $20.
哦,真的? 我还给了他20美元
- No. - Yeah.
- 不是吧? - 是的
- No way. - Yeah.
- 骗我吧? - 是真的
I didn't want that night to end.
我真不希望那一夜结束
You were right. It wasn't complicated.
你说的对,那时候其实不复杂的
I just wasn't ready to...
我当时只是没有做好准备...
You always talked about how you kind of liked the man...
你总是说喜欢...
who would approach you, speak his mind.
直率的男人
One who wasn't afraid to tell you exactly what he wanted.
能在你面前说出心里话
I did.
是的
But I wanted you to be that man.
不过我想要你成为那个男人
Well, why didn't you say something?
你怎么从来不说?
Reed, I'm saying it now.
瑞德,我现在就说了
Excuse me.
不好意思
I know it's not easy.
我知道,这不容易
Life hasn't changed that much for Reed, Sue, or Johnny.
对瑞德、苏和约翰尼来说 生活没有很大的变化
At least they can still go out in public. But for you...
至少他们还能抛头露面 但是你...
If you're trying to cheer me up, you're doing a hell of a job.
如果你来是想让我开心 那你做的太烂!
You know what I mean, Scarface?
你懂吗,刀疤脸?
I'm just saying I know what it's like to lose something that you love...
我只是想说 我知道失去钟爱的东西的滋味...
to see it slip away and know it's never coming back.
看着它就这么溜走 再也无法挽回
Look.
听着
Reed is gonna fix me up, okay?
瑞德会把我治好的,知道吗?
For your sake I hope you're right.
我也希望你是对的
Look, he's a brilliant man.
他是个非凡的人
We should all trust that he's working as hard as he can.
我们都应该相信 他会尽他所能地努力工作
You're his best friend.
你是他最好的朋友
So what possible reason could he have for taking his time?
他有什么理由不抓紧时间?
I mean, other than spending more time with Sue.
我是说,难道花时间在苏身上?
- Wow, I had no idea. - It's true.
- 喔,我一点也不知道 - 是真的
Yeah.
对
I have that effect on people.
是啊,人人看到我都是这种表情
Ben.
本
So you remember my name now, do you?
你现在记得我的名字了?
Do you also remember what you swore to do...
你还记不记得,你曾发过的誓...
with every breath in your body?
以你的生命发的誓?
We're working as hard as we can.
我们在尽全力工作了
Yeah. I can tell.
是啊,我看到了
- Victor was right. - Victor?
- 维克多是对的 - 维克多?
Ben, I don't know if this thing will change us back or make us worse.
本,我也不知道现在会让我们恢复 或是变得更糟
I need you to be patient for a little while longer.
你有点耐心,再给我点时间
Reed, look at me!
瑞德,看着我
I am looking. That's why I can't make a mistake.
我在看,正因为这样 我不能出一点错
I've gotta get it right and it's not right yet! We need to test it!
我必须保证它万无一失 可现在还没有,我们还要测试
I spent my whole life protecting you, and for what?
我这一生都在维护你 到头来,为了什么?!
So you can play Twister with your girlfriend...
为了你可以和你的女朋友谈情说爱...
while I'm the freak of the week?
而我在旁边像个傻子一样等着?
Ben, stop it!
本,住手!
- You stay out of this, Susie! - Stop it, or I will.
- 这不关你的事,苏 - 你住手,不然就关我的事
Get off me, rubber boy!
你给我下来,橡皮小子
You guys, quit it.
你们俩,都住手!
Calm down!
冷静
Good thing you're flexible enough to watch your own back.
好的是你足够灵活 能够自保
'Cause I ain't doing it no more.
因为我不会在保你了
You two are on your own.
你们两个靠自己吧
Look what the marketing guys gave me.
看,这是那些做市场推广的人给我的
Look, check it out, listen. You're gonna love this.
瞧,你会喜欢的
It's clobbering time!
来打架吧
It's catchy, right?
很上口,对不对
Isn't that great?
多好玩啊
That was the prototype.
嘿,这个是原始模型!
- Johnny, have you seen Ben? - Yeah, Sunshine just left.
- 约翰尼,你看见本了吗? - 是啊,太阳公公刚离开
Look, Sue, I'm sorry. I can't stand this freak show.
苏,对不起 我不能再呆在这个傻瓜秀里了
- I gotta get back to the real world. - You're calling that the real world?
- 我得回到真实的世界里去 - 你说那个是真实的世界?
Sue, stop. You're not Mum. Don't talk to me like I'm a little boy, okay?
苏,住口,你不是老妈 别把我当小男孩,好吗?
Maybe I would if you stopped acting like one.
可以,但你要先有个大人样
Do you even hear yourself? Who do you think you are?
你知道你在说什么吗? 你以为你是谁?
Why is everyone on my ass? If you guys are jealous, that's fine.
为什么你们都烦我? 如果他们几个是忌妒我,没关系
I didn't expect it to come from you, though.
尽管我没指望你们会嫉妒
You really think those people out there care about you?
你真的以为外面那些人喜欢你?
You're just a fad to them, Johnny!
他们不过是拿你当消遣,约翰尼
Let's try something new. You live your life, I'll live mine.
我们来点新的 你过你的生活,我过我的
Sound good?
没意见吧?
And just for the record, they love me!
而且记录备案,他们喜欢我!
Oh, God. Reed.
哦,天,瑞德
Oh, my God, Reed. What did you do?
哦,我的天哪,瑞德,你做了什么?
- I can make it work. - No!
- 我能成功 - 不
I need more power to control the storm.
我需要更多的电能来控制风暴
More power?
更多的电能?
- You need a doctor. Come with me. - Sue.
- 你需要一个医生,跟我来 - 苏
- One more try... - You need to rest.
- 再试一次... - 你需要休息
Leonard, bring me our lab rat.
莱纳德,把试验鼠带来
Ben. Come in.
本,请进
What is this? Where's Reed?
怎么回事?瑞德呢?
Where do you think? With Sue.
你认为呢?他和苏在一起
I'll take it from here, Leonard.
我来接手,莱纳德
Yes, sir.
是,先生
What do you want, Vic?
你要怎样?维克?
To help you.
帮你
The machine is ready.
设备已经好了
But Reed said it wouldn't
但是瑞德说…
He also said we'd avoid that storm in space...
他还说了我们可以躲过 太空中的风暴的...
but we all know how that turned out.
但我们都知道结果如何了
He couldn't generate enough power for the machine to reach critical mass.
他不能生成足够的电能 所以这个设备就不能达到临界质量
Yet another mistake for Mr. Fantastic.
这是神奇先生犯的又一个错误
- And you can? - Yes.
- 你可以? - 是的
Tell me...
告诉我...
do you want to be Ben Grimm again?
你想变回为本 格莱姆吗?
Thank you.
谢谢
Vic?
维克?
Vic, it worked.
维克,成功了
Everyone thought I was safe behind those shields.
每个人都以为我在防护罩后面 就是安全的
Oh, my God.
我的天
The machine worked for me. It can work for you, too!
这个机器在我身上能成功 也能把你治好
It did, Ben. It worked perfectly.
对啊,本,它在我身上也成功了 非常成功
- You planned this. - I've always wanted power.
- 这一切都是你的安排 - 我总想得到力量
Now I have an unlimited supply.
现在我有了无穷的源泉
And no Thing to stand in your way.
什么都挡不了你的路
Take a good look, Ben.
好好看看,本
This is what a man looks like who embraces his destiny.
这样的才是男人 拥抱他的命运
One down, three to go.
搞定了一个,还有三个
Vic?
维克?
Right on cue.
刚刚好
Ben?
本?
- What did you do? - Exactly what I said I would.
- 你都干了些什么? - 正如我所说的
I built a better, stronger being.
我创造了一个更好 更强壮的物种
And outsmarted the great Reed Richards.
我比伟大的瑞德 理查德斯更聪明
If you've exposed yourself to the storm, you're endangering your life.
如果你让你自己暴露在风暴之下 会危及你的生命
- You need help. - You always know best.
- 你需要帮助 - 你总是什么都知道
So tell me, what happens when you superheat rubber?
那么告诉我,如果超高温加热橡胶 会怎么样?
No!
不
Mr. Von Doom, are you okay?
方杜先生,你还好吗?
Never better, Jimmy.
再好不过了,吉米
Why the long face? Let's talk in my office.
怎么拉长了脸,不高兴? 我们到我的办公室里谈
Ben.
本
Sue!
苏
Johnny, the machine worked!
约翰尼,这个机器起作用了
Give me a hand. Come on.
帮我一把
Get his arm.
抓着胳膊
You all right, Ben? Put him on the step.
你没事吧,本?把他放到台阶上
What happened, big guy? I leave you for five minutes...
发生什么事了,大家伙 我们才离开了五分钟...
The machine.
那个机器
Vic used it on himself. He was affected by the cloud like us.
维克多把它用在他自己身上 像我们一样,他也受了风暴云的影响
- Where's Reed? - Vic must have taken him.
- 瑞德在哪儿? - 一定是被维克带走了
Dr. Richards, allow me to begin your lesson.
理查德斯博士 请允许我开始给你上课
Chemistry 101.
化学知识 第一章
What happens to rubber when it's supercooled?
橡胶在超低温的环境下 会怎么样?
Give up?
放弃吗?
That's not like you, Reed.
这可不像你,瑞德
After all, we're both doctors.
毕竟我们俩都是博士
Painful?
痛苦?
You don't know the meaning of the word.
你还不懂这个词的真正含义
Just a little something from our defence contracts.
给你看看我从国防部拿到的新玩意
Let's check in on the rest of the family, shall we?
我们现在来关注一下剩余的家庭成员 怎么样?
We gotta get out of here!
我们得离开这儿
Wait a minute. I got an idea!
我有个办法
- Don't even think about it. - Never do.
- 想都别想 - 从来就不想
What are you doing? Johnny, no!
你在干什么!约翰尼,不!
Come on, flame on!
快,快点,火来
We have to help Reed.
我们必须去救瑞德
It's too dangerous for you now. You have to stay here.
现在对你来说,太危险了 你留在这儿
What did I do?
我都干了些什么
Come on, think!
快,想想!
Two down, two to go.
搞定了两个,还有两个
Sue.
苏
- What has he done to you? - How romantic.
- 他都对你做了些什么? - 真浪漫
Victor, please.
维克多,请不要这样
Call me Doom.
叫我 杜（末日）
The machine works. It worked on Ben, it can work on you. We can turn you back.
那个机器成功了 它可以把本变会来,你也可以
Do you really think fate turned us into gods so we could refuse these gifts?
你们真以为命运把我们变成上帝 维克多,你一直就以为自己是上帝
Victor, you always thought you were a god. Now back off.
维克多,你一直就以为自己是上帝 你走开
Susan, let's not fight.
苏,我们不要打架
No. Let's.
不,我们打
Susan, you're fired!
苏珊,你被解雇了!
Marco.
马可
Polo.
波罗
Did you say goodbye to your brother Johnny?
和你弟弟说再见了?
It's time to end this!
是时候结束了!
No, Vic. It's clobbering time.
不,维克,该打架了
Damn, I've been waiting to do that.
妈的,就等着这一刻呢
Susie, you okay?
苏,你还好吧?
Victor ain't that bad, huh?
"维克多也不算太坏,啊?"
"He's just a little larger than life", right?
"他就是有点妄自尊大",对不对?
Maybe next time you'll listen to me before...
也许下次你该先听听我的...
Ben!
本!
- Sorry, ladies. - Stop the car!
- 对不起,女士们 - 停车
Pull over. Hit the brakes!
靠边,踩刹车
This is the police.
警察
Put your hands up and step down from the vehicle!
举手然后下车出来!
Take him out!
开枪!
Ladies, I'm gonna need to borrow your car.
女士们,借你们的车用一下
- The transmission sticks. - Not gonna be a problem.
- 变速杆是坏的 - 这个没关系
I can't let you do that!
我不能让你这么做
Reed?
瑞德?
I'll be right with you.
马上就轮到你
Hello, Susan.
你好,苏珊
You three are pathetic.
你们三个可怜虫
You missed me.
少了我
Had a little relapse, huh?
又聚到一起了,啊
- Welcome back. - This is gonna be fun.
- 欢迎回来 - 这将会很有意思
I can't hold it!
我支持不住了
Johnny, supernova!
约翰尼,超新星!
I thought we agreed that was bad.
我记得我们一致认为那个东西不好
Now!
快点!
- Ben! - Gotcha.
- 本! - 接住你了
Sue! Think you can contain it?
苏,看你能不能包住它
Flame on, kid.
燃烧吧,火鸟
Is that the best you can do?
你就这点儿本事吗?
Time for your lesson. Chem 101.
现在给你上一课 化学知识 第一章
What happens when you rapidly cool hot metal?
给热金属快速冷却会怎么样?
Ben!
本!
You done good, kid.
干得不错,小子
Come on.
来
Sue, you okay?
苏,你没事吧?
Yeah.
没事
Man, I love this job.
我爱死这个工作了
Job, huh?
工作?
Well, we do have the suits.
不过,我们的确有制服啊
Ladies, your drinks.
女士们,你们的酒
- I don't think we need another. - Just one more.
- 我看我们已经喝够了 - 再喝一杯
Thank you, thank you so much. Cheers!
十分感谢,干杯
I need names and shots.
告诉我你们的名字 还有你们要喝几杯
Bartender!
酒保!
They're custom-made, 36 EEEE.
特别定制的,36号,4倍E码
Well, look. I've been crunching the numbers on the machine.
听我说,我一直在分析机器上的数据
And I think if I can rework the power settings
我想如果我可以重新调整能量
Forget about it, egghead. I'm good as is.
算了,我现在挺好
Better than good, baby.
我们可不只是一般的好,亲爱的
You just need to work on your touch.
你得好好练习你的力度
I like the sound of that.
我喜欢这个声音
- Can I talk to you for a second? - Sure.
- 我能跟你谈一会儿吗? - 当然
Thanks.
谢谢
I found a broken gasket from space.
我在太空里找到一个破垫圈
A gasket?
垫圈?
- Reed, come on, we're at a party. - And if one of us were to wear it...
- 哦,瑞德,我们在开派对 - 我想我们中的一个也许可以戴着它...
No more thinking.
不再有更多的考虑
No more variables.
不再有更多的变量
Sue Storm...
苏...
will you marry me?
你愿意嫁给我吗?
Sue, you kind of need to say something.
苏,总得说些什么啊
Yes.
我愿意
That's my nose, genius. These are my lips.
那是我的鼻子,天才 这才是我的嘴唇
She's kissing him.
他们在接吻
That's so cute.
真好
About time, you guys.
正是时候,伙计们
No more wisecracks about the way I look.
嘿,不许再对我的样子说三道四了
Call me Mr. Sensitivity.
叫我敏感先生
Okay. Wide load coming through. Everybody move, he's huge.
注意,大型卡车过来了,大家让路
- Come here, Mr. Sensitive. - Flame on.
- 你给我过来,敏感先生 - 火来
Showoff!
爱现!
How long will it be?
要多久?
Should be about 12 days.
大约12天
（拉脱维亚）